GOKSEL ERYIGIT

Front-End Developer

http://geryit.com me@geryit.com +90 (532) 581-9818 Alanya, Turkey 07400

ABOUT ME

I'm 29 year old UI/UX Developer living in Turkey who has worked on projects for some of Turkey's biggest web agencies and worked on online projects for clients such as: **Amnesty International**, **Resfest**, **Bridgestone**, **Honda** and **Starbucks**.

I'm currently part of the international jury of AWWWARDS.

EXPERTISE

Professional capabilities

- High-quality and responsive front-end development for web sites and applications.
- Modular, scalable, robust, and reusable code.
- Performance optimisation, progressive enhancement, usability, and accessibility.
- SEO using semantic HTML and Microformats.
- Site planning and architecture.
- User interface design.

Technical skills

- Expert in hand-coded (X)HTML and CSS.
- Expert knowledge of HTML 5 and CSS 3 specifications.
- Working knowledge of jQuery.
- Experience working in PHP MVC environments.
- Development for Magento, Shopify and Wordpress open source platforms.
- APIs such as Facebook, Google, Flickr and Twitter.
- Experience working with Git and SVN.

EXPERIENCE

Senior UI/UX developer

Freelance / April 2011-Present

User Interface / User Experience developer working on *freelance* project. Responsible for implementation Web user interface and interaction elements based on screen designs, wireframes, flowcharts and other documentation using HTML5, CSS3 and hand-coded Javascript

Freelance front-end developer

~ in Istanbul & Stockholm / January 2010-April 2011

Front-end developer working on various projects. Improved CSS3 and HTML5 skills. Projects I worked on: DJ Hero, Betterfly

Front-end developer

~ at Trafo / February 2008–January 2010

Worked with the Trafo Interactive team to rapidly plan and create reusable, responsive, front-end. Worked on online projects like <u>Amnesty</u> International Turkey, Bridgestone Turkey and Starbucks Kahve Tutkusu.

Web developer

~ at Litespell / October 2006-November 2007

Utilized an expert knowledge of JavaScript, HTML, DOM, CSS and Actionscript to deliver advanced user interfaces and controls. Built the front-end for Honda Turkey web site.

Web developer

~ at Sanalnet / October 2001–March 2002

Applied HTML to deliver cutting-edge user interfaces and components. Handled markup maintenance and development for various online projects.

WORK

National Geographic Turkey Microsite (2011) /

http://natgeo3d.ficturkey.com

Activision DJ Hero II (2010) / http://www.djhero.com

Bridgestone Turkey (2009) / http://www.bridgestone.com.tr

HONORS,

Representing Turkey, have been featured as one of the international jury

AWARDS AND ARTICLES

members in the Awwwards annual book published in 2011 & 2012 http://geryit.com/lib/awwwards-book-screenshot.jpg

- Awwwards interview http://geryit.com/lib/awwwards-interview.pdf
- Selected as one of the international jury members in the Awwwards http://www.awwwards.com/jury/8
- The Css Awards (Site of the Day) Gazel, Inc. http://www.awwwards.com /web-design-awards/gazel-inc
- The Css Awards (Site of the Day) Mind Work 3D http://www.awwwards.com/web-design-awards/mindwork3d
- The Css Awards (Site of the Day) Geryit http://www.awwwards.com /web-design-awards/geryit

EDUCATION

Anadolu University

~ BMA, Business Administration / 2009–2012 (Will be graduating in September of 2012)

Dokuz Eylul University

~ Geophysical Engineering / 2002–2004 (Dropped out second year)

Anatolian High School / 1998-2002

TIONS

RECOMMENDA "Goksel is a highly creative and fast front-end developer. While working with us on Betterfly.com, his passion about his work made him work late hours and weekends to meet deadlines with no complaints, making him a valuable member of our team. He has a great personality and I look forward to working with him on future projects",

February 19, 2010

- ~ Emily Pugh, Interactive Producer, Betterfly
- "I had the opportunity to work with Goksel on redesigning our website (www.zaplee.com). Working with the designer, Goksel created a website that has been recognized as a leading example of aesthetics, flow and user interaction. He's been outstanding both in programming and the communication surrounding the project. Highly recommended if you want complex front-end programming within budget, time and excellent quality. I just hope you don't take too much of his time as we are looking forward to him doing some additional work in the very near future.", February 1, 2010

- ~ Mihir Kothari, IT Consultant, Zaplee
- "I worked with Goksel over about a 6 months's time on web development, and he's fantastic to work with. He's an ace developer with a unique skill set that spans extensive front-end to back-end development. I worked with him on several projects and i can say that he is a great developer to add to any team.",

February 2, 2010

~ Yavuz Akyazici, General Manager, Trafo

 $Twitter \cdot LinkedIn \cdot Email$